Mikhail Tsoy

+381631256794 | mikhail.tsoy123@gmail.com | Belgrade, Serbia

Summary

Frontend developer with more than 1 year of experience. My goal is to create interfaces that are not only user—friendly, but also help businesses achieve their goals.

I'm a versatile frontend developer and ex-UX/UI designer, well versed in HTML, CSS, JS, Typescript and React.js. I have experience in fullstack development using node.js and express.js. Worked in various teams with flexible project management methodologies. I can quickly dive into new subject areas. I'm able to find a common language with developers and managers from different countries and time zones.

Before moving on to frontend development, I worked as a UX/UI designer for 4 years. Designed interfaces for projects of various scales, from crypto-exchanges to federal projects. Collected requirements, conducted UX research and designed design-systems.

Portfolio: https://mikhailtsoy.vercel.app

Skills

HTML, CSS, SASS, React.js, Redux, Typescript, JavaScript, Vue.js, English, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Git, UX, UI

Experience

Freelance

Frontend developer | 06/2022 - Present

- Development and creation of user interfaces for various web projects.
- Work closely with clients to define project requirements and objectives.
- Designing and implementing the user experience using modern technologies and frameworks such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React and Vue.js.
- Optimizing the performance and availability of web applications to increase user satisfaction.
- Participation in all stages of development, including interface design, layout, programming and testing.
- Regular interaction with customers for feedback, changes and updates of projects.

NAUMEN | Saint Petersburg

UX/UI Designer | 03/2021 - 12/2021

- Designed the interface for a large service desk product, in close collaboration with analysts
- Created a highly informative dashboard and a map-based application for project management
- Maintained an organized internal knowledge base for all design materials

CRP lab I Saint Petersburg

UX/UI Designer | 05/2020 - 12/2020

- Designed interfaces for a variety of projects, including a crypto-exchanger, SPDM systems, and CRM systems for universities and European banks
- Gathered requirements, created wireframes and prototypes, designed visual elements, and tested designs to ensure they
 were user-friendly and intuitive
- · Communicated effectively with colleagues in different time zones in both Russian and English

EPAM | Saint Petersburg

Experience designer | 01/2018 - 01/2020

- Conducted UX research, including interviews with users, personality analysis, and competitor analysis
- Designed interfaces, created wireframes and prototypes, and tested designs to ensure they were user-friendly and intuitive
- · Maintained an organized design system for all design materials

Education

JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures Masterclass | 12/2022

- Gained knowledge and experience in analyzing code complexity, recursion, and common programming patterns.
- Acquired skills in implementing searching and sorting algorithms, manipulating data structures, and applying Dijkstra's Shortest Path Algorithm.
- Focused on building a problem-solving approach to develop solutions to complex problems.

Yandex.Practikum

Web development | 09/2022

- Learned modern web development technologies to become a junior frontend developer, including expertise in HTML, CSS, JS, React.js, and Git.
- Developed several projects ranging from static one-page websites to SPAs with both frontend and backend components.
- Gained basic knowledge of Node.js and experience setting up servers using express.js and working with git and the WebPack project builder.
- Successfully completed training by creating a portfolio website that is both adaptive and responsive, reviewed and passed by a mentor.

Saint Petersburg State University of Telecommunications | Saint Petersburg Information Technologies and Communication Systems | 07/2019 GPA: 4,3/5

Paper on Research of the ACM mode of the DVB-S2 standard and its implementation into the digital television network

Languages

English, Russian